全速前进!
Everybody get a move on!
全副武装 继续行进!
We're loading on the run!
向林木线前进!
Head for the tree line!
血仇
全体后退!
Fall back!
我们务必坚守住战略高地
We'll make our stand on the ridge.
后方注意隐蔽!
Cover your backs!
1863年
恶魔的骨气 - 西维吉尼亚州
冲啊!
Come on, let's go!
继续前进!
Don't stop!
敌人来了!
Here they come!
冲啊! 冲啊 前进!
Come on! Come on, let's go!
快点
Come on.
我真想把这些该死的扣子剪下来 兰德尔
I'll cut them damn buttons off, randall.
给你当靶子用
Makes you a target.
至少我晚上的时候不会挨冻
At least I can stay warm at night.
你是怎么让你的裤子不掉下来的?
How are you still keeping your britches up?
大自然补给
Nature provides.
这边走!
Over here!
寻找掩体 重新装弹!
Take cover and reload!
你的那条胳膊看来保不住了
You're gonna lose that arm.
如果能保命的话
I'll give the arm.
这条胳膊不要也罢
Just want to live.
敌人来了!
Here they come!
不要开枪!
Don't shoot!
停火
Hold fire.
北方佬冲过来了
Yankee cavalry coming.
保留体力 全力奋战
Company strength.
北方佬冲过来了
Yankee cavalry coming.
保留体力 全力奋战
Company strength.
我们可能这样完了 昂斯
This could be it, anse.
最好祈求保佑吧
Best make your peace.
好吧 我以前从来没指望过上帝 兰德尔
Yeah, well, I never courted god before, randall.
我怀疑他现在不愿听我祷告
I doubt he'll hear me now.
注意左侧!
On the left!
这里守不住了
Can't hold this.
带战士们退到防线后面
Get the boys back to the line.
告诉他们把手枪留给我
Tell them to leave the pistols with me.
快点起来! 撤退!
Soldier, on your feet now! Move!
我们准备撤退!
We're moving out!
大家把随身佩带的手枪
Them that's got sidearms,
放在这个麻袋里
put them in this sack here.
快点 撤退!
Come on, let's move!
快走
Go on.
我跑得比你快
I'm a faster runner than you are.
听着 昂斯
Hey, anse.
我会为你祈祷
I'll pray for you.
我们撤退!
We're moving out!
给我个了结
Make it stop.
让我摆脱痛苦
Make the hurt stop.
噢 噢 孩子
Oh, oh, hey.
让一切结束
Make it go away.
就这样
That's it.
对 很好
Yeah, that's good.
我带了点饼干和豆子回来
I'll take some of them biscuits and beans.
手枪还给你们
Got your sidearms back for you.
哦 上帝啊
Well, I'll be.
你消灭了多少北方佬 恶魔 昂斯?
How many yanks you kill, devil anse?
你怎么逃出来的 队长?
How'd you get away, captain?
真他妈是个奇迹
Damn miracle.
昂斯
Anse.
你在做什么?
What do you think you're doing?
我不想看着那些
Well, I ain't stayin' to watch
我们刚从死神手里救下来的孩子们
the boys we just saved
为一场注定失败的战斗而牺牲
die for a lost cause.
注定失败?
Lost?
你不会真的是这么想吧
You don't believe that.
确实如此
I do.
拜托 如果每个士兵自己心里都觉得
Come on, what do you think would happen
这场战争注定失败
if every soldier decided for himself
你觉得会发生什么?
when the war was lost?
战争将更快结束
Be shorter wars for sure.
不要再为此找借口了 兰德尔
Don't make a cause no better, randall,
好人都白白牺牲了
when good men die for it in vain.
从此刻开始 我只为自己的家人而战
From here on out, I fight only from home.
我们就是你的家人
We're your home.
你不能扭曲事实来迎合你自己
You can't just twist things to suit yourself.
你这是逃兵
This is desertion.
我可不这么认为
I don't look at it that way.
从我参军开始我就抛弃了我的家人
I figure I deserted my family when I signed up.
明智点跟我一起走
You'd be wise to come with me.
你发过誓的 昂斯
You took an oath, anse.
我们发誓要"宁死不屈"
We swore "death before dishonor."
没有什么可以改变这一事实
Nothing changes that.
万一有一天我不得不处决你呢?
What if I'm on that firing squad that has to put you down?
如果真有这么一天 千万不要手软
Well, if it comes to that, don't flinch.
这样做是不对的 我不会让你这么做的
This is wrong. I can't let you do this.
好好照顾自己 兰德尔
You take care of yourself, randall.
今日之恩感激不尽
Many thanks for today.
上帝痛恨逃兵
God hates deserters.
西弗吉尼亚州 马特湾
你该给你的狗买杯喝的 吉姆叔叔
You ought to buy your dog a drink, uncle jim.
再来一点这个
And a little of this.
再来一点那个
And a little of that.
闻起来也不错 是不是?
Smell good too, don't you?
死狗
Damn dog.
你那件衣服是从北方佬尸体上扒下来的吗?
You get that coat off a dead yankee?
不 不是
No, I did not.
你在厕所里捡的吗?
You find it in an outhouse somewheres?
不 不是
No, I did not.
那么你从哪里弄到的?
Where'd you get it then?
整个叛乱期间我都穿着它
I wore it throughout the rebellion.
我的侄子
My nephew,
"恶魔" 昂斯・哈特菲尔德
"devil" anse Hatfield,
北方美利坚合众国(简称联邦) 南方美利坚联盟国(简称邦联)
是美利坚联盟国军队里面光荣的一员
proudly serves these here confederate states of america,
你的哥哥也是 兰德尔
as does your brother randall.
而你竟敢
Yet you dare come in here
穿着那件该死的军外套来这里
and wear that goddamned bluebottle jacket,
你个狗娘养的
you son of a bitch
这附近很多人
Near as many around these parts
都为了邦联战死沙场
are fighting and dying for the union.
对我而言 战争已然过去
As for me, war is passed,
而我没有其他衣服可穿
but I ain't got another jacket.
不过 我现在有点热
Howsomever, being as how I'm getting a little hot in here,
我会把衣服脱下来的
I will take it off.
记在账上
Put it on my charge.
你敢不敢把那件该死的北方佬的衣服丢在地上
You're gonna throw that damn yankee jacket on the floor,
然后在上面撒尿
and you're gonna piss on it.
我要回家了
I'm going on home.
不在乎这里是香是臭
Don't much care for the perfumed stank in here.
连酒钱都付不起
Can't even pay for your drink.
你他妈的还算什么男人?
What kind of a damn man are you?
如果你想找麻烦的话
The kind who, you wanna come after,
我随时奉陪 吉姆・万斯
you'll find ready, Jim Vance.
我可不像你的亲戚
Unlike your kinfolk here,
我可不怕那些
i'm not afeard of no man
把自己的狗当妓女用的人
on account of he uses his dog for a whore.
别跟他一般见识 吉姆叔叔
Leave it now, uncle jim.
西弗吉尼亚州 拖轮河谷
你们两个兔崽子
Do you bluebellies
知道对付窃贼的处罚是什么吗?
know the penalty for thievery?
求您了 先生
Please, sir.
我们只是太饿了
We were just really hungry.
仅此而已
That's all.
求求您了 先生
Please. Please, sir.
我们只是...
We were just...
我不想听解释 一直往前走
I don't want to hear it. You just keep walking.
我有一个绝好的计划
I got a good plan for you boys.
别白费口舌了
Quit your lollygaggin'.
饭桶
Git.
哦 天啊!
Oh, my god!
你要把他们带到哪里去 吉姆叔叔?
Where you taking 'em, uncle jim?
昂斯・哈特菲尔德 你回来了!
Anse Hatfield, you're back!
站住 混蛋们
Hold up, you bastards.
你这是在保卫前线呢
Guarding the home front, I see.
是的
Yep.
没有什么可以逃过老吉姆的手掌心
You know nothing gets by old jim.
这些北方佬偷玉米的时候被我抓个现形
I caught these yankee shit heels a'pilfering corn.
他想杀了你 侄子
He meant to take your life, nephew.
我不会这么做的 我们只是太饿了
I never. We was just hungry.
我在他的眼里看到了杀意
I saw murder in his eye.
求求您了 先生 不要杀我
Please, sir. Don'm t hit lekill me.
走吧 北方蠢货
On your way, yankee bill.
走啊
Go on.
是我的话早脚底抹油了
And I'd hurry it up.
我还以为你会放他一马
And I thought you was letting him go.
他也这么想
So did he.
在你把他一枪打得脑袋开花之后
After you blew out the other one's brainpan,
我还有其他选择吗?
what choice did I have?
确实
Yep.
不能留下目击证人
Don't want to leave no witnesses.
无所畏惧地死去
Died unafraid,
才是一个男人应有的死法
how a man should die.
真他妈的可惜
That's a damn shame.
那个北方小畜生本可以活下来的
That yankee piss pot should've suffered.
是的 但是既然你如此痛恨他们
Yeah, well, you hate 'em so much,
当初你为什么不参军呢?
how come you didn't sign up to fight 'em?
受命于人去战斗本身就是一种失败
Fighting on others' terms is how you lose,
我不能接受这种失败
and losin' is intolerable to me.
那么 既然我回来了 我依然还是家族掌门人
Well, I'm back now and still head of this family.
我无条件服从
I ain't gonna be no problem.
很好
Good.
那么我现在命令你
Then you'll understand when I tell you
把这些尸体从马路上拖走
to get these bodies off the road,
藏到不会被发现的地方
somewhere no one ever finds 'em.
是的
Yeah.
就和以前一样
It's gonna be like it was before.
看看豪尔斯先生 一直微笑着
Lookit Mr. Howls over there, all smilin'.
它很高兴你回来了...
He's glad you're back too...
一如往昔的心思缜密
With all your fine plans.
把尸体处理好
Get the bodies off the road.
你究竟在那里做什么?
What were you doing in there anyhow?
还没到家 就喝得满身酒气 惹是生非
Not even home yet and you get yourself into a drunken fight,
你个没用的蠢货
you shiftless fool.
我将藏匿在酿酒场
I'm hidin' out at the still
直至吉姆・万斯的骚动平息
till this ruckus with Jim Vance blows over.
你最好就喝死在那里
You'll drink yourself to death up there.
我不是去赴死的
I ain't going up there to die.
我是为了好好活着
I'm going up there to stay alive.
你错了
Ain't right.
从军队回来以后
Come home from the army,
把我当奶牛一样就知道让我生
breedin' me like I was cattle,
你现在又想一走了之吗?
then you take off again?
你难道忘记自己丈夫和父亲的职责了吗?
No, you've got your duties as a husband and father.
孩子们 我不在家你们要照顾好妈妈
Kids, mind your mama while I'm gone.
我们会的
We will.
莉瓦西
Levicy.
安德森?
Anderson?
我受够了战争
I'm done with the war.
你再也不回去了吗?
You ain't going back?
我已经受够了
I've given enough.
亲爱的 我平安回来了
I'm back for good, darling.
上帝保佑 你平安回来了
Lord, you lived through it.
我们的孩子怎么样?
How's our little boy?
我们的小天使入睡了
He's an angel now that he's asleep.
天哪 看看你
oh, my god, look at you.
有件事你一定得知道
You'll want to know
去年我们收了至少六十蒲式耳的玉米
that we got at least 60 bushels of corn in last year,
我们没有挨饿
so we ain't starvin',
今年的收成也会很不错
and this year promises to be just as good,
所以你不用操心
so you don't have to worry none,
约翰斯 还有 你绝对认不...
and johnse, you will not recog...
我们明早再说
We'll get to all that come morning.
西弗吉尼亚州 垂山
嘿!
Hey!
那不是玛莎・麦考伊吗?
Ain't that martha McCoy?
利亚斯替一下
'Lias.
麦考伊夫人
Miss McCoy.
你应该听说了我家哈蒙的情况
Suppose you heard about my harmon.
他在酿酒场待了一个多月 饮酒度日
He's up at that still over a month, drinking.
说万一他现在收手
Says if'n he stops now,
当吉姆・万斯杀上门的时候
he'll throw a fit and be helpless
他将既愤怒又无助
when Jim Vance come to kill him.
女士 不只是对我的吉姆叔叔来说
Ma'am, your yankee husband was a traitor
你的北方丈夫是个叛徒
to more than just my uncle jim.
在这的许多弟兄
There's lots of folks around here
都无法宽恕哈蒙的背叛行经 或许...
can't forgive harmon's betrayal and might...
或许他们也很想取他性命
Might want to kill him,
其中不乏有你的一些亲戚
even some of your own kin.
但哈蒙就只指控了你的吉姆・万斯叔叔
But your uncle Jim Vance is the only one my harmon accused
和他的猎狗通奸
of fornicating with his hound dog.
这个...
Well...
这真是低劣的用词
That's a poor choice of words.
找个藏身之所确实是明智的行为
I'll admit, hidin' out was prudent.
我不想变成一个寡妇苟活
I can't survive being a widow.
我叔叔总是我行我素
My uncle tends to go his own way.
但下次我见到他
But next time I see him,
我会尽力相劝
i'll do what I can.
南茜 坐下
Nancy, sit down.
我知道你在这!
I hear ya!
你抓不住我的 你这狗崽子!
Ya ain't getting me, you son of a bitch!
爸爸?
Pappy?
"亲爱的兰德尔"
"Dear Randall,"
"时运艰难"
"our fortunes are bitter."
"哈特菲尔德传话说"
"Your brother harmon was done murdered,"
"你的弟弟哈蒙被谋杀了"
"it is said by Hatfields.
"我们也只能勉强度日"
"The rest of us barely scrape by."
"亲爱的丈夫 如果你还活着"
"If you are still alive, dear husband,"
"愿你速归"
"i pray that you come home to us soon."
"爱妻 莎莉"
"Your loving wife, sally."
结束了!
It's over!
战争结束了!
The war is over!
李将军属南方邦联
李将军投降了!
General lee surrendered!
- 上帝保佑! - 这场战争终于结束了!
- Praise the lord! - The war is over!
感谢上帝 感谢耶稣
Thank you, thank you, jesus.
真见鬼
Now, I'll be damned.
对某些人来说战争永不休止
Won't be over for some.
战争真他妈是一种浪费
War was a goddamn waste.
我可不想让和平成为战争的祭品
I don't intend to waste the peace.
肯塔基州
谁?
Who's there?
转过来
Now turn around.
兰德尔?
Randall?
莎莉 是我
Sally, it's me.
你憔悴了不少
You've aged some.
北方佬干的
Yankees done it.
在监狱里我们简直是猪狗不如
Treated us worse than animals in that prison.
我并非打算放弃你 我的丈夫 但我别无选择
I didn't want to give up on you, husband, but I think I did.
首先 从我这片林子里砍十英亩树...
First we log my ten acres here...
越过山脊直至丘陵后背
Run from the ridge across and outside that hill.
然后呢?
Then?
我们从中获利
We take the money from that.
就可以再买二十英亩的地
We buy 20 more acres.
买完地呢?
Then what?
再买四十英亩
Buy 40 more.
这就像用马车轮擦你的屁股一样
It's like wiping your ass with a wagon wheel.
没完没了的?
Ain't never gonna end now, is it?
哈特菲尔德先生
Mr. Hatfield.
我是兰德尔・麦考伊的表弟兼律师
I'm a cousin of randall McCoy, an attorney.
我叫佩里・克莱因
My name is Perry Cline.
我在路易维耳市的
I studied law at the offices
伊桑・麦基宾办事处学习法律
of ethan mckibbin in louisville.
去年十月通过了律师考核
Passed the bar last october.
我对即将造成的不快…
I apologize for any unpleasantness
提前致歉
we're about to have.
克莱因先生 有话直说
Just state your business, mr. Cline.
我知道你自认为
Now, I know you believe
自己拥有这片林地
you own this stand of timber
并有权利进行砍伐
and have the right to cut.
然而依据相关法律规定 并非如此
Whereas, in fact, in the eyes of the law, you do not.
你的想法究竟从何而来?
Where in thunder did you get that?
这林地是我老爹1859年
My daddy bought this parcel
从一个越南佬手里买的
off of bucky hand in 1859.
那份契约还躺在家里的一个盒子里呢
I got the deed in a box at home.
我当然相信你 哈特菲尔德先生
I believe you, Mr. Hatfield.
但他把这木材卖给了我的表兄拉瑟福德
But he sold my cousin Rutherford,
现在由我来打理他的财产
whose estate I administer,
早在1858年6月22日就获得木材采伐权
the timber rights beforehand on june 22, 1858.
签字并得以见证 瞧?
Signed and witnessed, see?
那越南佬是我家的一个朋友
Well, bucky was a friend of my family.
如果我们只买了地没买木材
He'd have told us
他不会不告诉我们的
if we'd not bought the timber with the land.
你这是在逼我起诉 哈特菲尔德先生
You'll force me to sue, mr. Hatfield.
你得承担所有的损失
You'll be liable for damages
还需要支付迄今为止你所砍伐的所有木材
and the cost of all my timber you have cut to date.
你输定了
You will lose.
那是威胁吗?
That a threat?
我想你还是去起诉更安全
I reckon it's safer you sue.
在没有听到法官异词之前
Without they hear different from a judge,
我的亲戚会以为你在试图敲诈
my relatives might think you just tried to bamboozle me.
那好吧...
Well...
我已表明自己的权利
I've informed you of my rights.
且看法律如何裁决
We'll see what the law has to say about it.
祝你愉快
I bid you good day.
我已准备好尽妻职责
I'm prepared to do my duty as your wife,
但我请求把种子播在我体外
but I ask that you spill your seed outside of me.
我难以承受再育一儿
I could not bear another birth.
? 我主为何流出宝血 ?
Alas and did my savior bleed
? 愿意忍受死亡 ?
and did my sovereign die
? 甘愿代替 ?
would he devote
? 卑微的我 ?
the sacred head
? 遍历痛苦悲怆 ?
for such a worm as I
? 借我主十字架 ?
at the cross, at the cross
? 我得见主恩光 ?
where I first saw the light
? 除罪恶重担 ?
and the burdens of my heart
? 我心洁净 ?
rolled away
? 借十架我信仰 ?
it was there by faith
? 眼明亮心平康 ?
I received my sight
? 到如今 不分昼夜 ?
and now I am happy
? 快乐欢畅 ?
all the day
? 我主为何流出宝血 ?
alas and did my savior bleed
? 为何忍受死亡 ?
and did my sovereign die
? 甘愿代替 ?
would he devote
保重
Well, then, take care.
很高兴再次见到你
Now, good see you again.
很高兴见到你
Nice to see you.
兰德尔 很高兴见到你
Randall, good to see you.
多多保重 谢谢您的到来
Now, take care. Thank you so much.
兰德尔!
Randall!
别闹了
Oh, now, stop fighting.
莎莉
Sally.
莎莉 我们聊聊吧
Sally, you come talk with me.
约翰斯 过来
Come on, Johnse.
来
Come on.
快来
Come on now.
没想到你会在耶和华殿里
Hard to reconcile you in the lord's house.
莉瓦西硬拖我来的...
Yeah, well, Levicy dragged me here to...
真的很高兴见到你 兰德尔
It's good to see you, Randall.
我担心...担心你死在了战场上
I feared...feared you dead.
很多次我都觉得我已经死了
Times I felt like I was.
剩下的兄弟们...或死或失踪 只剩我一个
Rest of the company...all lost, all dead, except me.
莎莉 我们的丈夫都回来了
Our men are home now, sally.
你的是回来了
Yours is.
我丈夫似乎只回来了一半
Mine is only half home.
我说选举那天来看看吧
I mean to enter the election day contest,
当然我尊重你的选择
and I would value your opinion.
拿着
Go ahead.
接骨木果酱?
Elderberry?
没有比这更甜的了
There's nothing sweeter.
不堪设想你都经历了些什么...
It's terrible bad what happened to you...
监狱和所有的一切
Prison and all.
如果有什么可以帮忙的地方
If there's anything I can do to help out.
你是在为你的背叛寻求良心安慰吗?
You propose now to ease your conscience for deserting?
还是为我弟弟的死?
Or for my brother's murder?
是你那个吉姆叔叔干的
Your uncle Jim done it.
如果他在这 我会当面质问
If'n he was here, i'd say it to his face.
吉姆发誓他跟哈蒙的死无关
Jim swears he had nothing to do with harmon's death.
你居然买他的账?
And you believe that?
我不懂与人争执 兰德尔
Well, I have no knowledge to the contrary, randall.
况且吉姆叔叔他...他在上帝面前发了誓的
And uncle jim, he...He swore before god.
哈特菲尔德家族的人要上帝有什么用?
And what use do Hatfields have of god?
就这么说定了 你拿着 尝尝
Well, you keep that, and you try it.
如果这做得...
Let me know if'n it set up and...
谢谢
Thank you.
我不明白...
I don't understa...
太平绅士 瓦伦丁・哈特菲尔德
早安
Mornin'.
我要给你看样东西 克莱因先生
There's something I'd like to show you, Mr. Cline.
差不多要开庭了
Court's about to convene.
是的 我知道 我想你会很期待这东西的
Yeah, well, I think you'll wait for this.
艾利生・利亚斯
Ellison, 'lias,
给克莱因律师看看我们的证据
show lawyer cline our evidence.
你说哈米什1859年为你那张契约作了见证
You recall that hamish was witness on your bill of sale
但原来发现他
in '59 but somehow died,
早在1857年时就入土了
got himself buried in '57.
有印象吗?
You recall that?
我怎么就被假证给耍了
I am somehow made a victim of a fraud.
也不知道我怎么就...
How is not clear to me...
或许你应该跟法官好好解释一下
Maybe you oughta should just fetch the sheriff.
也许他可以帮你缉拿那个
Perchance he can help you track down the scoundrel
把你骗得团团转的骗子
what sold you a bill of goods.
显然这是个变数 哈特菲尔德先生
Obviously this changes things, mr. Hatfield.
是啊
Yeah.
我撤诉
I forgo.
我放弃索取在你土地上的砍伐权
I abandon and renounce claim to the timber rights on your land,
并为我的草率感到抱歉
and I apologize for being hasty
并提出了一起无效的索赔
and putting forth an invalid claim.
你应该得到赔偿 必须的
You deserve to be compensated. You shall be.
我身上有二十二美元
I have $22 here.
把你的钱收起来
Keep your money.
我别无它意 哈特菲尔德先生
I take that kindly, mr. Hatfield.
事业刚起步的年轻律师
Young lawyer starting his career,
轻易就被一份伪造证件给耍了 形势不妙啊
deceived by a forged document don't look well.
太不妙了
Don't look well at all.
人们甚至不禁会开始猜想
People might even start to think
你从中也掺了一脚 并搞得一团糟
that you had a hand in this forgin' and then bungled it.
你想干嘛 哈特菲尔德先生
What do you want, mr. Hatfield?
你想要得到所有属于我的东西
Well, you meant to have all that was mine.
所以我也要得到你的一切
So I must be entitled to have all what's yours.
至少是你从你父亲那继承的部分
At least what you inherited from your daddy.
那可是五千亩地啊
That's 5,000 acres.
我不贪图你的林地
Don't hardly much want the land.
我只要伐木权
Just the timber rights.
我想我们没必要闹到法庭上 是吧?
I don't believe we have to go in court at all, do we?
找不到 老爹
Can't find her, pa.
该死的
Consarn it.
继续找
Keep looking.
只是一只小猪而已
It's one little pig.
而且很可能被山狮吃了
Mountain lion probably got her.
那只猪如果养肥了可以够我们吃一个冬天
That pig fattened up feeds this family for a whole winter.
明白吗 孩子?
You understand that, boy?
灾难折磨着我们
Misfortune afflicts us both.
抱歉让你失去了林地 表弟
Sorry about you losing your land, cousin.
但是 他们的背信弃义改变不了
Still, we cannot let our paths be diverted
我们的原则
by the treachery of others.
相信上帝 多做善事
Trust in the lord and do good,
你就会得偿所愿
and he shall give thee the desires of thine heart.
完成了 爸爸 你喜欢吗?
All done, poppy. You like it?
剪得很好 罗斯安娜
Fine job, roseanna.
给
Here.
我一直想把这个给你
I've been meaning to give you this.
金纽扣?
A gold button?
这是战争中得到的
It's from the war.
给我吗?
For me?
因为你是我的最爱
'Cause you're my favorite.
或许你是对的 兰德尔
Perhaps you're right, randall.
但我不会放松警惕
But I would not drop my guard.
战争改造了人
War changes men.
到了和平时期 他们就变成
Peacetime can turn them into
诡计多端的蛇
scheming snakes.
我猜哈特菲尔德会不停地来找你
I predict Hatfield will keep coming at you
假装友好而慷慨
feigning friendship and generosity.
当他这么做时
And when he does,
你就会知道我是对的
you'll know I'm right.
我就觉得会在这找到你 兰德尔
I hoped I might find you here, randall.
就像从前一样 对吧?
Almost like old times, huh?
什么风把你吹到城镇来了?
What brings you to town?
生意
Business.
我刚刚和金克斯・克莱布瑞特达成协议
I just made a deal with jinx clabberat
将他的一些部分好的低洼地转让给我的人
to farm out some of his good bottomland with my boys.
我们可以种一些经济作物
We might just grow us a big cash crop of tobaccy.
很好
Good.
你是来这炫耀
You come to boast about stealing
从我表弟佩里・克莱因那里夺来的成果吗?
from my cousin Perry Cline?
没有人来这炫耀 兰德尔
Nobody come here to boast, randall.
我只是想向你示好
I'm just-i'm just trying to be friendly.
我不知道你听说了什么
I don't know what you heard,
但我没有一样东西是从你表弟那夺来的
but nary a thing was stole from your kin.
当我揭穿佩里・克莱因的谎言时
Perry Cline gave me his timber rights
他就把伐木权给了我
when I uncovered how he was trying to cheat me.
我当时就该打爆他该死的脑袋
I should've blown his damn head off is what I shoulda done,
但是...
but...
你认为我这是阴谋诡计 你..
You think I profited unfairly, you...
你拿着这个
you take this.
你凭良心收下
You take that in good conscience.
这是不是让你饱受折磨呀?
Does it weigh on you at all, captain Hatfield,
你轻松获利 而其他人坚持到底
how you profited while others stayed the course
却受苦受难?
and suffered for it?
没有人能质疑我付出 了多少
No man questions what I gave the cause, randall.
尤其是你
Especially you.
再来一杯
'nother one.
1878年
西弗吉尼亚州 拖轮河谷
传言说 这里要建一条铁路
Talk is, they're gonna build a railroad right through here.
那样我们的木材就可以运往各个地方
Then we'll send our timber in all directions
遍及全国
'round the whole country.
我希望不要运往北方
Not up north, I hope.
战争早就结束了
War's long over, jim.
没有南北之分
There's no north, no south-
只有赚钱的人和不赚钱的人
Just people who got money and people who ain't.
我打算和他们做生意
I mean to do business with them that has.
我一直都坚信我们会发财
I always knew we was gonna be rich.
嘿!
Hey!
威廉 你的孩子!
It's your boy, william!
树倒了!
Tree fell!
木渣掉进了他的眼睛!
Splinter caught his eye!
我看不到!
I can't see!
埃迪 我什么也看不到!
Eddie, I can't see!
为什么我看不见?
Why can't I see?
我知道很难受 孩子
I know it hurts bad, son.
我很佩服你 佩服你能忍受这么大的痛苦
I admire how you-I admire how you standin' up to it.
给我一些水
Give me some water.
约翰斯 为什么我看不到?
Johnse, why can't I see?
我们马上送你看医生
We're gonna get you to a doctor straightaway.
昂斯
Anse.
你不会死的
You're not gonna die,
但我不想撒谎
but I won't lie to you.
你伤得很重
This is a serious wound.
你好 邻居
Howdy, neighbors.
兰德尔
Randall.
莎莉夫人
Miss sally.
你还好吗 浮洛伊德?
How do you do, floyd?
大好的日子 是吧?
Blessed day, ain't it?
当然啦
Sure is.
你这季收成如何?
How's your harvest this season?
一般般
Fair to middlin'.
比上不足
Better than the last one.
比下有余
Not as good as the next.
你的猪养得好肥
Your hogs fattened up nice.
哦 坏脾气的小家伙
Ah, ornery critters.
孩子们和狗试图圈住它们时
Had the kids and dogs try to round them up,
它们就不停地哼哼
but these two kept a'squealin' off.
告诉我 你养这个斑点猪
Tell me, floyd, how long have you had
多长时间了?
that spotted shoat there?
呃 去年的
Well, he bred last year.
我知道它什么时候养的
I know when it was bred.
我在它耳朵上做了记号
That's my markin' on its ears.
哦 不 兰德尔 你弄错了
Ah, no, randall, you're mistook.
我特意在我的猪上做了记号
I notch my swines particular
这样我就不会弄错
so I do not get mistook.
呃 你知道的 小猪很喜欢到处跑
Well, you know young pigs is wanderers.
我想我的一两头猪或许正挂在你的厨房里
I expect you gots one or two of mine hangin' in your smokehouse.
我不会
I do not.
你到底还偷了多少我的猪?
How many more of my pigs you took?
你偷了多少我的猪肉来填饱你的肚皮?
How much pork you takin' from my family to stuff your belly?
等会儿 兰德尔 这是个大罪名
Now, hang on, randall. That's a serious accusal.
你是想吵架吧
You's bein' quarrelsome.
我就是了 怎么样?
I am, am i?
试试这个怎么样?
Well, how's this for quarrelsome?
该死的偷猪贼 浮洛伊德・ 哈特菲尔德
Damn you for a pig thief, floyd Hatfield.
驾
Come on.
快走 饭桶
Come on, git.
你们全家人都跟你一个德行!
I guess all you Hatfields are the same!
你吃饱了吗 佩里?
Did you get enough to eat, Perry?
谢谢
Thank you.
多么优雅的莎莉阿姨
An elegant sufficiency, aunt sally.
太优雅了
Elegant sufficiency.
罗斯安娜 帮我清理桌子
Roseanna, help me clear the table.
爱丽菲尔 你去清理小的那桌
Alifair, the little one.
浮洛伊德・ 哈特菲尔德
This matter of floyd Hatfield
偷走了你的牲畜...
and the theft of your livestock...
他撒谎还当着我的面抵赖
He lied and denied it to my face.
起诉他
We sue.
我们要把法律看成我们的肌肉
It's useful to think of the law as a muscle.
像肌肉一样 法律是越用越强
Like a muscle, it can be strengthened with proper use.
使用太少 它就会变弱
Used too little, it becomes feeble
弱到无法保护你
and too weak to protect you.
你说得很好 佩里
That's fine talk, Perry.
你很有天赋
You got the gift.
浮洛伊德・ 哈特菲尔德在河的另一边
Floyd Hatfield is on the other side of the river.
那里由哈特菲尔德的人当法官
Where a Hatfield sits as judge.
我可以安排陪审团审案
Mm, I can arrange a jury trial.
我们安排六个麦考伊的人
We'll sit six McCoys
和六个哈特菲尔德的人
and six Hatfields.
虽然不能为你可怜的被杀的兄弟讨回公道
It won't get you justice for your poor murdered brother.
但赢得这场官司也是一种公道
We win this case, it's a kind of justice nonetheless.
我觉得这样愚蠢至极
It strikes me as foolish.
此话怎讲 女士?
How's that, ma'am?
为了一头猪上法庭
Goin' to court over a pig.
弄得我们像愚蠢的乡下人
Makes us look like some village idiot.
莎莉...
Sally...
我想 最终
I suppose, in the end,
上帝会惩罚所有的罪人
god punishes all transgression.
但是 你应该知道
But, as you well know,
通常 上帝想要我们
oftentimes the good lord expects us
帮他实现愿望
to be the instrument of his will.
你怎么看 吉姆?
What say you, jim?
起诉他
I say we sue.
眼睛怎么样了?
How's the eye doing?
一片浑浊 看不见了
It's gone milky, capped over.
嗯哼
Uh-huh.
- 让我瞧瞧 - 不 吉姆
- Let me see. - No, jim.
- 别这样 让我瞧瞧 - 吉姆
- Come on, let me see. - Jim.
看看嘛
Let me see it.
转过去
Turn around.
我在这干嘛?
What am I doin' here?
支持你的家族
You're supporting your family.
就为了一只猪?
Over a pig?
昂斯
Anse.
拿走
Put it away.
我要叫你队长(captain)
I'm gonna call you captain.
简称盖子(cap)
Cap for captain.
就像你爹一样
Like your daddy.
表明你是一个伟大的伐木者
Shows you're an important feller.
盖子是个好名字 不是吗?
Good name, cap, hmm?
是 我喜欢极了
Yeah, I like it.
嗨 沃尔叔叔!
Hi, uncle wall!
现在开庭
Court is in session.
感谢在场的陪审员
Thanks to those of you on the jury
参加此次审案
for coming here today and agreeing to serve.
我知道你们大多数都有作物和牲畜需要照料
I know most of y'all got crops. Stock needs tendin'.
所以我不会耽误你们
So I ain't gonna keep you from your task
太多时间
any longer than necessary.
尊敬的哈特菲尔德法官 陪审团成员
Judge Hatfield, members of the jury,
我们要将法律当作肌肉
it is useful to think of the law as a muscle.
正如肌肉一样 法律是越用越强
Like a muscle, it can be strengthened with proper use.
克莱因先生
Mr. Cline.
你的话越少
The briefer you make your remarks,
你胜诉的可能性就越大
the better your case is gonna be received.
活该 饶舌之人
Serves you, windbag.
请坐!
Sit down!
你要宣证人吗?
Do you mean to call witnesses?
兰德尔・麦考伊先生和他的妻子莎莉
Mr. Randall McCoy and his wife, sally,
都看到了那头猪的耳朵上
both saw the McCoy markin'
有麦考伊所作的标记
on the ear of the hog in question.
哦 看来没必要请他们站出来
Oh, now, I don't think we need to call 'em to the stand
你说就好了
just to say so.
所以简而言之
So to put it plain,
麦考伊一家说那是他们的猪
the McCoys say it is their pig
有他们所作的记号
and their notch,
而浮洛伊德否认
and Floyd says that ain't so.
对么?
Is that clear?
是的
Sure.
今天那只猪上庭了么?
Is the pig in court today?
没
No, it ain't.
为什么?
Why not?
那个...
Well, um...
它已经被吃掉了
It's done been et.
那好 浮洛伊德
All right, Floyd.
在你宰了它之前 有谁能证明猪耳朵上的记号
You got any witness saw it before you butchered the swine
是你刻上去的?
to say it is your notch?
我不知道要找人证
I didn't know I needed one.
不过如果你给我几个小时
If you give me a couple hours,
我也许能找到
I might could come up with somebody.
我见过
I seen it.
那只肥猪
The hog in question, that is.
我看到浮洛伊德割下了它的耳朵
And I seen floyd actually cut that shoat's ear.
噢 需要我向圣经之名宣誓吗?
Oh, do I need to say I seen it on the bible?
我劝你别那样
I'd advise you not to.
我记得那只猪的后腿上有黑点
That pig had black spots on its hams, as I recollect.
还有浮洛伊德作记号时 手滑了下
And Floyd's hand slipped when he notched it.
差点切下他的大拇指
Pretty near cut his thumb off.
不管怎样 如果那只猪是浮洛伊德偷来的话
Anyways, why would Floyd show him that swine
怎么还会让我们看到?
if he stole it?
那不是没道理么
It don't make no sense.
好了 比尔
That's enough, Bill.
我认为比尔・斯塔顿的证词
I trust y'all give Bill Staton's testimony
所言非虚
the respect it deserves.
阁下 我还没说完 你看...
Your honor, I ain't quite done, you see...
你坐下!
You sit down!
陪审团的成员们
Me Mbers of the jury,
有谁认为猪是浮洛伊德・ 哈特菲尔德的?
who thinks the hog belonged to Floyd Hatfield?
好的 有谁认为猪是兰德尔・麦考伊的?
All right, who believes the hog was Randall McCoy's?
- 这里 - 是的 先生
- Here. - Yes, sir.
塞尔柯克・麦考伊
Selkirk McCoy,
你没投这边是要投给那边是么
you didn't vote one way or t'other.
他投给兰德尔叔叔了
Well, he votes uncle Randall.
让他自己说 帕里斯
He has to be the one to say so, Parris.
我想做公正点
Well, I'm trying to do the right thing here.
你们看 我虽然是麦考伊家族的人 但...
You see, I am of the McCoy family, but...
事实上 在心底
Well, the truth is, deep down
我真觉得猪是浮洛伊德・ 哈特菲尔德的
I do believe that pig was one of Floyd Hatfield's razorbacks.
判决立刻出来了
Judgment's goin' down in a second.
请尊重麦考伊这个姓氏
Do not disrespect the name McCoy.
比尔・斯塔顿发誓
Bill Staton swears on his oath
他亲眼看到浮洛伊德割出了那个切口
that he seen Floyd cut that notch.
你这个满口谎话的卑鄙小人
You are a lying spawn of hell
你投他是因为你和哈特菲尔德的太太有一腿!
that voted his Hatfield wife's apron strings!
哦 兰德尔 这...
Oh, Randall, this...
别把她扯进来
Leave her on out of this.
别因为一头猪
Gonna give yourself apoplexy.
就气得中风了
All this to-do over a pig.
这关乎声誉
This is about honor,
关乎谎言 偷窃 以及谋杀
about lyin' and stealin' and murderin'.
这与本案无关
That is not pertinent to the case.
这关乎罪孽 恶魔昂斯!
It's about sin, Devil Anse!
基督徒的权力和诅咒!
What's christian right and damnation wrong!
麦考伊!
McCoy!
这一案件被驳回了!
This case is dismissed!
所有人都出去!
Everybody get the hell out of here!
老天作证 谁再鼓动作乱
By god, I will gut-shoot the next agitator
藐视法庭 我就要开枪了
who further disrespects my courtroom,
不管是麦考伊还是哈特菲尔德家的人
McCoy or Hatfield.
在哈特菲尔德家的法庭
I reckon this is what I shoulda expected
我早猜到会这样了
from a Hatfield court.
麦考伊 你再多说一个字
One more word out of you, McCoy,
只会让我看不起你
i'll hold you in contempt.
最好注意下你高傲的态度
Best watch your high-and-mighty ass,
麦考伊牧师
preacher McCoy.
送你一句经文:
Here's scripture for you:
"杀人流血 接连不断"
"blood toucheth blood."
你不想走这步的 科顿
You don't want to make that move, Cotton.
看吧 你爸爸不会告诉你这些
See, your daddy won't tell you that
是因为他想打倒你
'cause he's trying to beat you.
谢了 沃尔叔叔
Thanks, uncle Wall.
是啊 谢谢你 沃尔叔叔
Yeah, thanks, uncle Wall.
不管怎样 我想说
Anyway, what I'm saying is,
你站在那里最终也毫无帮助 昂斯
you standin' up there in the end didn't help things, Anse.
是啊 事情还在掌控中
Yeah, well, I had it under control.
看你干的好事
The hell you did.
这些小争吵却成了一个致命的导火线
These picayune squabbles got a way of turning deadly.
也许吧 但我不能再让兰德尔・麦考伊
Maybe so, but I cannot have Randall McCoy
继续为难我们了
continue to embarrass us.
一点小小的尴尬
A little embarrassment's
好过不公正的裁决
better'n what grows out of injustice,
你觉得呢?
don't you think?
当我发誓看到那头猪后腿上有黑点时
You see the look on ol' Randall McCoy's face
你们有没有注意兰德尔・麦考伊脸上的表情?
when I swore that pig had black spots on his hams?
你喝多了 那么大声
More you drink, louder you get.
这些麦考伊如果找我麻烦的话
Them McCoys come after me,
我会像砍佩里・克莱因的树一样砍他们
i'll cut 'em down like Perry Cline's trees.
我会阉了他们
Hell, I'll even nut 'em.
你想再说一次么?
You wanna say that again?
我很愿意拿你这根小牙签
I'd just love to take away that arkansas toothpick of your,
插进你屁眼里
shove it straight up your stinkin' asshole.
我是说如果麦考伊因为
I said any McCoys come after me
我在法庭上说的那些来找我麻烦的话
for what I said in court,
我会撂倒他 我会阉了他
i'll take 'em down, and I'll nut 'em.
我猜你可能是有那么蠢
Well, I suspect you might be stupid enough to try.
你...你叫我出去 是么?
You...you callin' me out, hmm?
别在这里
This ain't the place.
狗嘴里吐不出象牙 比尔・斯塔顿
But you got a mighty big mouth, Bill Staton.
好了 别做傻事 坐下吧...
Okay, nothin' to do but just sit here...
任何麦考伊家的人来找我麻烦
Any McCoy come after me and do me harm,
我都会撂倒你们的!
i'll take you down!
过来啊!
Come on!
嗯! 你们怕了吗?
Eh! What, are you scared?
很有趣吧 臭虫 嗯?
That was fun, Skunky, huh?
你觉得好玩么? 你觉得开心么?
You had fun with that? You happy with that?
你知道么 你胆真肥
You know, you're brave.
我再也不跟你一起喝酒了
I ain't gonna drink with you. I ain't gonna drink with you.
你好啊 昂斯
Howdy, Anse.
我想我告诉他们了
I guess I told 'em, huh.
如果看到一只恶狗在睡觉 你会去吵醒它么?
You see a mean dog sleeping, do you go pester him?
- 不会 先生 - 不会
- No, sir. - No, sir.
它醒了 你会去打它么?
He awake, you go kick him?
你也不会
No, you don't.
你会让它呆着 它可能会继续回去睡觉
You leave him alone, maybe he goes back to sleep.
你懂我的意思了么?
You get my point?
懂了 但是那些可恶的麦考伊家的人...
Yeah, but those shit-butt McCoys...
我们互相理解了么?
We understand each other?
是的 先生
Yes, sir.
? 我不喝酒 也不抽烟 ?
I don't drink, and I don't smoke
? 但是我玩了你的女人 ?
but I give your girl a poke
? 我玩了你的女人 ?
I give your girl a poke
? 我说过我不抽烟 ?
I said that I don't smoke
? 我玩了你的女人 我玩了你的女人 ?
I give your girl a poke, I give your girl a poke
下午好 比尔
afternoon, Bill.
你想阉了我们?
You want to nut us?
我抓住你们啦 哈?
I got ya both, huh?
我们在这 比尔
Here we are, bill.
你还想撂倒我们
You still want to take us down,
阉了我们么?
cut off our balls?
来吧
Go ahead.
我们要不要阉了他?
Should we nut him?
快走 快走
Come on, come on.
该死
Shit.
快跑
Come on.
恶魔昂斯在外面
It's devil anse.
一个人?
Alone?
是啊 他一个人还不够么?
Well, ain't he enough?
混蛋们!
Sons a bitches!
别杀我们
Don't you slay us.
盖子...
Cap...
我在 爸爸
Yeah, pa.
捡起他们的枪
Pick up them guns.
把这些败家子带回去
Let's get these wastrels back across the river.
这是一个适合绞刑的好日子
It's a nice day for a hangin',
是吧 兰德尔?
ain't it, ol' Randall?
恶人吉姆・万斯
Mean Jim Vance.
近距离看起来
Well, you're not all that much.
你也不怎么样嘛
I mean, up close-like.
你算那根葱?
Who the hell are you?
噢 我叫托尔伯特・麦考伊 是兰德尔的儿子
Oh, I'm Tolbert McCoy, son of Randall.
我一直很想见见那个杀了我叔叔的人
See, I always wanted to meet the man that murdered my uncle
并且亲口告诉他他的好日子也快完了
and tell him his days are comin'.
你没资格跟我说这样的话
Not from the likes of you,
你个乳臭未干的黄毛小子
you wet-eared prick-chafing little shit.
在我像扇一只小鸡一样扇你之前滚出我的视线
Get out of my sight before I snap you like a chicken neck!
托尔伯特
Tolbert.
我们有正事要干
We're here on other business.
滚开!
Move!
我的两个侄子
What are my two nephews doing in there
为什么被锁在这个冰冷的尸体旁边?
being locked up next to this godforsaken corpse?
这是自食其果
You live with what you done,
如果可能的话
you might think twice before doin' it again
你们就该三思而行
if you should so get the chance.
法官 我恭敬的请求保释金
Judge, I respectfully request that bail be set
应该调至一个合理的数目
at a reasonable amount.
否决
Denied.
这两个男孩被指控犯了死罪
These boys stand accused of a capital crime.
我不会让这个案子拖很久的
And I will not have this business dragged out to fester.
给我个理由
You want to tell me why
我不该以谋杀罪吊死他们么?
I shouldn't hang 'em both for murder?
作为一个哈特菲尔德家的人
Bein' a Hatfield,
你很难做到完全公正
you're hardly impartial.
我是今天的正式出庭律师
I'm the attorney of record here,
我来回答这些问题
and I'll answer the questions.
比尔・斯塔顿被谋杀了
Bill Staton threatened to kill
有麦考伊家的人路过
any McCoys that crossed his path.
现在我们有目击证人看到
Now, we got witnesses to that.
帕里斯和山姆路过遇到了他
Parris and Sam did cross his path,
然后斯塔顿想杀了他们
and Staton did try to kill them,
最后反而被帕里斯和山姆自卫所误杀
then was killed himself by parris and sam in self-defense,
这两个守法的年轻人感到很内疚
which these law-abiding young men deeply regret.
阿门 我们确实很内疚
Amen. We surely do.
因为自卫而失手误杀
We's real sorry we had to do it,
我们感到非常抱歉
defending ourselves like that,
但是比尔・斯塔顿逼得我们走投无路
but Bill Staton give us no choice.
不管怎么样 法官
In any event, judge,
你没有权力审判死刑罪
you got no authority to try a capital case.
明白
Noted.
昂斯 在我宣布之前你有没有什么想说的?
Anse, you got anything to say 'fore I pronounce sentence?
比尔・斯塔顿 是个不错的工人
Bill Staton was a tolerable worker,
总是把赚到的钱给他母亲
always gave money to
还一直帮他搬运柴火
and got wood in for his mother
直到去年冬天她去世
till she died last winter.
他的确喝多了
He did drink a bit.
帕里斯和山姆都知道比尔只是威胁...
Parris and Sam both knew that Bill's threats-they both knew...
他们就像空酒瓶一样无知
That they was empty as the bottles they was comin' from.
很明显他们想报复他因为他乱说话
They wanted to revenge his mouthin' off, plain and simple.
然后等在那里
Then they lay in wait to get it.
这是有预谋的凶杀
That's premeditated homicide,
根据法律和万能的上帝
for which accordin' to the law and your almighty god,
他们应该被绞死
they had oughta hang.
你说话直冒傻气
You're talkin' like a fool.
死在这的这杂种醉鬼
This lowlife drunkard lyin' dead here
威胁说要灭了我全家
threatened murder on my family!
够了!
God damn it!
都给我过来坐下 然后闭上嘴
Y'all just get over here and sit down and shut up.
我们都知道是帕里斯和山姆杀了比尔・斯塔顿
All of us know parris and sam killed bill staton.
只是案情详情还不明确
Only the circumstances remain in question.
实在太令人羞耻了
It's a damn shame
居然没人告诉他们在大街上朝醉鬼开枪
no one told 'em shootin' a drunk on the road
是错的 为此受绞刑更是不值
was wrong and not worth hangin' for
连做个榜样都不够格
or even the price of the goddamn lead.
而更令人羞耻的是
And it's also a damn shame
居然没人阻止他的雇工
that no one stopped his hired hand's
酒后口出狂言
liquored-up threats and curses
导致两个红了眼的傻蛋犯下杀人罪
from inflaming two fools to commit murder,
一切本可避免发生
which was damn easy to foresee.
我裁定你们俩有罪
I find you both guilty of this heinous crime,
你们将即刻被
for which you are to be taken
送往指定地点
to some convenient spot without delay
处以绞刑 直至断气
and thereby hanged by the neck until you are dead.
由于你们之中无人能证明
A sentence which I hereby suspend
是在正当防卫或不是 以上裁决宣告无效
since no one can say whether it was self-defense or not.
走吧 孩子们 快滚出去
Go on, boys. Get the hell out of here.
谢谢您 先生
Thank you, sir.
在这呢!
Right there!
卡尔文 无罪释放!
Calvin, not guilty!
我就知道你老爹肯定能把咱们弄出去
I knew your daddy would get us out of there.
苍天明鉴
As god as my witness,
我决不允许这场审判
I will not allow my court
成为两家开战的导火索
to be the cause of a war between our two families.
看在他去世的母亲的份上 比尔・斯塔顿
Bill staton ain't worth it and his ma, who he did do right by,
不该遭此一劫
is dead and gone.
愿她的灵魂安息
God rest her soul.
就这么记:
Write it in the book:
沃尔・哈特菲尔德法官
"miscreants discharged
放走了歹徒
by judge wall Hatfield."
谢谢 法官阁下
Thank you, judge.
你今天绝对做到了公正贤明
You've been a fair and wise man today.
绝对的
Indeed.
上帝是公平的 出来混
God is just and shall return to us
迟早是要还的
the years that the locusts hath eaten.
好吧 你还真是自我感觉良好啊
Well, you're just a huckleberry above a persimmon,
不是吗?
ain't ya?
若你两人还不能好好反省自己的所作所为
If you two don't mend what's wrong between you,
地狱之火必会燃起
hellfire's gonna certainly rise up and consume
直至烧毁两个家族
both our families.
谢谢 克莱因先生 阁下
Thank you, Mr. Cline, sir.
- 这就对了 - 干的太漂亮了
- That's right. - That's mighty fine work.
老爹 我们接住他了!
We got him, pa!
今天运气不错
It is a good day for it.
- 快点上马车 孩子们 - 好耶!
- Get up in the wagon here, boys. - Whoo!
你他妈有什么好开心的?
What the hell you laughing at?
看看这是谁? 信了吧!
Look who it is, huh? Believe it!
最好是信了!
You better believe it!
1880年 选举日
悠着点 孩子
Whoa, easy now, son.
你现在还不想让它爆吧
Don't want it going off just yet.
对呀 笨蛋
Yeah, mush-head.
别把我们都给炸飞了
Don't blow us all up,
你这弱智杂种
you half-wit bastard moron.
过来 给我过来!
Come here. Come here!
觉得有意思? 过来啊
Find it funny? Come here.
道歉
Apologize.
嗯 对不起你这杂种了 科顿
Yeah, I'm sorry you's a bastard, cotton.
好好说!
Tell him!
好吧 好吧
All right. All right.
对不起
I'm sorry.
你这道歉一点没诚意
That ain't good enough.
我很抱歉那么称呼你
I apologize for what I called you
我以后绝不会再那么叫你了
and won't never call you no names again.
老爹 你不用那么做的
Didn't have to do that, pa.
每个人都叫我笨蛋
Everybody calls me mush-head.
科顿 你是与众不同的
Well, you ain't like everybody else, cotton.
上帝给了你一副宽广的胸怀
God gave you such a big heart,
所以不能再给你充满智慧的脑袋
he couldn't very well give you a whole abundance of brains,
你说是不?
now, too, could he?
我想是的
I guess not.
可我确实是杂种啊
I am a bastard, though.
听我说 孩子
You listen to me, boy. Hmm?
杂种是不会有人来爱的
A bastard's got no family that loves him.
你是这样的吗?
Is that you?
你没人爱吗?
不 不是的
No, it's not.
你是我儿子
You're my son.
不然为啥给你起名艾利生?
Why do you think your first name's ellison?
现在 让它飞起来吧
Now, let's see it fly.
让大家都退后
Get everybody back now.
好嘞
Okeydokey!
大家都往后站站
Everybody stand back now!
我说不行
Nuh-uh. I said no.
我就趴这了 管你们怎么弄
I gotta make a livin' here, god dang it.
想喝免费的威士忌
You want free whiskey,
你得和那边的托尔伯特・麦考伊去说
you go talk to tolbert McCoy over there.
我会去的
I might do that.
现在别看
Don't look now.
约翰斯・哈特菲尔德 正盯着我们呢
Johnse Hatfield is staring at us.
我真希望有只乌鸦冲下来把他眼睛啄走
I sure hope crows swoop down and pluck his eyes out.
说什么呢 南茜
What a thing to say, nancy.
他的舅舅吉姆・万斯杀了我爸
His uncle Jim Vance killed my pap.
你又不能肯定
You don't know that for sure.
每个人都这么说
Everybody says so.
别听他们瞎说
Don't make it for sure.
他很帅倒是真的
He sure is handsome.
恶魔昂斯的儿子
Son o' devil anse.
从没见过长的这么勾魂的魔鬼
I ain't never seen no devil look like that.
- 嘿 盖子 - 有事吗?
- Hey, cap. - Yeah?
还有罗伯特 过来看着点
Robert e., you all take over.
我的好侄子
My favorite nephew.
那真是浪费
Now that's just wasteful.
你好 罗斯安娜・麦考伊
Hello, roseanna McCoy.
我叫约翰斯・哈特菲尔德
I'm johnse Hatfield.
我知道你是谁
I know who you are.
是表示你懒得搭理我吗?
Does that mean you won't talk to me?
就因为我是哈特菲尔德家的
Me bein' a Hatfield and all.
我没特别针对你
I don't mean you no harm.
是吗 可我就是这么觉得
Well, now, that's the way I feel.
我不明白干嘛弄那么麻烦
You know, I don't see why there's been so much trouble.
我打赌你不知道我也曾姓麦考伊
I bet you didn't know I was named for a McCoy.
是的 女士
Yes, ma'am.
想去看看西弗吉尼亚的
Hey, you want to go see the second most beautiful sight
第二美景吗?
in west virginia?
我是不是该问问
So then am I supposed to ask
第一美景是什么?
what's the first most beautiful sight?
当然 如果你想看的话
Well, if you wanna go.
那你就会说 远在天边 近在眼前
Then you're just gonna say, "oh, you are."
就像你跟埃洛伊丝・詹金斯
Just like you told eloise jenkins
还有其他无数女孩说的一样
and about a dozen other girls.
我早听过你那些风流事
I've heard all about you.
要是关于我的谣言都是真的话
Well, if all the gossip about me was true,
我早是个长犄角还甩尾巴的怪物了
hell, I'd have horns and a spiny tail.
你穿的这什么靴子
Those are some mighty interesting boots
有意思
you're wearing.
- 你喜欢? - 不 我没那么说
- You like 'em? - No, I didn't say that.
那...
So...
西弗吉尼亚的
What is the second most beautiful sight
第二美景在哪呢?
in west virginia?
现在 我就带你去
Well, now, i'll take you there.
- 你郑重发誓吗? - 是的
- Do you solemnly swear? - Yeah.
谢谢 哈特菲尔德先生
Thank you, Mr. Hatfield.
这对忙碌的家庭主妇来说实在是一种恩惠
This really is a boon to busy housewives.
你一定会对它相见恨晚
You'll wonder how you got by without one of these.
有了我这种申请过专利的排气阀
You'll never fear a scalding explosion
和这个可变压力计
with our patent release valve
您就再也不用担心被烫伤了
and the variometric pressure gauge.
兰德尔 很不错吧?
Oh, randall, isn't it just fine?
谢谢你的讲解
Thanks for the demonstration.
蒸汽压力锅
Steam digester.
可以节省时间的发明
Time-saving application...
真是个蠢玩意儿
It's a silly trinket.
没有这什么双层压力锅
I've been puttin' food on the table all these years
这些年我也照样做出饭菜
without I had me some pressurized double boiler.
哈特菲尔德能满足他老婆任何要求
Hatfield can offer his wife any new contraption she wants.
总有一天我也会给你买个小神奇回来
One day I'm gonna buy you some miracle,
比如爱迪生・费勒发明的电暖炉
like that edison feller's electric fire.
他爹 我才不需要那东西的
Poppy, I don't need anything like that.
你需要的 女士
Yes, ma'am.
总有一天 莎莉 我要给你买个
Someday, sally, i'm gonna buy you
三项插头的双层压力锅
a double boiler that runs on electrical-tricity.
这小提琴卖多少钱?
How much you want for the fiddle?
那是我的
It's mine.
我要一块五
I want a greenback and a half for it.
给你50美分
I'll give you four bits.
是从我奶奶那传下来的
It were my grandpappy's.
75美分
75 cents.
欠你二十五美分 再把酒给我满上
I'll owe you a quarter and you fill my cup.
这是我的蒸馏装置
Oh, yeah, this here's my drip still.
了不起吧?
Ain't she a beauty?
我能生产 大概...
I could produce maybe...
我不确定 一天半加仑
I don't know- A half gallon a day
上好的西弗吉尼亚玉米威士忌
of fine western virginia corn liquor.
这是上好的蒸馏装置
I mean, this is the horse's head still,
然后钞票自然来 你懂得
a cash can, you know.
这是我自己建造的
I built this rig myself.
我从老爹那借钱买的这些部件
I mean, I borrowed the money to buy the parts from my pa.
为了活个人样
I figure, make a good livin',
以后好养家糊口
support my family proper.
没准以后就在离这不远的地方
I may even build me a cabin not far from here
为我和我妻子建一栋小屋让她在那安胎
for my wife to have babies in.
你有妻子了?
You got yourself a wife?
你这是寻我开心呐
Come on. You're teasing me, I know.
我只知道一个事实
Well, one thing I know for a fact:
你有一车皮的女朋友
you got girlfriends by the bushel.
我对她们都不是认真的
I ain't serious about none of 'em.
瞧那傻蛋
Look at that mush-head.
真想按住那小牛犊子把他呛死
You're s'posed to drown the runt of the litter.
像这样...
Like this...
这呢 过来
Here. Come on.
人多才有乐子嘛 是吧?
Easy to laugh in a bunch, ain't it?
跟我来
Come on.
你姐姐呢?
Where's your sister?
我不知道她去哪儿了
Oh, I don't know where she went.
去找找
Well, go find her.
我们得走了
We're leavin'.
让她再玩会儿吧 兰德尔
Let her stay, randall.
小伙子们会送她回去的
The boys will bring her home.
托尔伯特
Tolbert!
务必要把罗斯安娜带回来 听见没?
You're to bring roseanna home without fail, ya hear me?
是的 先生
Yes, sir.
你接吻过几次?
How many times you been kissed?
祖母之类的不算吗?
Not countin' grandmas and such?
不算
Not countin'.
大概就几次吧
A couple times, maybe.
我打赌你从未试过真正的吻
I bet you ain't never really truly been kissed right.
不是我吹牛 但...
Not to boast, but...
大家都知道我是个接吻高手
I believe I have a strong reputation as a good kisser.
好了
There.
现在你可以说你接过吻了
Now you can't say you've never been kissed.
天哪 天都黑了
Good lord, it's gettin' dark.
我们得走了
We ought to get goin'.
罗斯安娜! 罗斯安娜!
Roseanna! Roseanna!
罗斯安娜!
Roseanna!
罗斯安娜 我们要走了!
Roseanna, we are leaving!
她不在这儿
She ain't here.
一定是和麦克林托克家的人
Must have rode back with the mcclintocks
或克莱因一起回去了
or Mr. Cline.
怎么也不跟我们说一声
Well, she could have told us.
爸爸会骂死我们的
Pa's gonna take our damn heads off.
罗斯安娜!
Roseanna!
罗斯安娜 最后机会!
Roseanna, last chance!
罗斯安娜!
Roseanna!
最后机会 罗斯安娜!
Last chance, roseanna!
噢 保佑他们还在
Oh, please let them be here. Please.
噢不
Oh, no.
噢 不!
Oh, no!
不瞒你说 都走了 连你的亲戚们也走了
Upon my honor, they's all gone, even your kinsfolk.
噢 天哪
Oh, god.
爸爸会杀了我的
My poppy is gonna kill me.
我该怎么回家?
How am I gonna get home?
我带你回家
Well, I'll take you with me.
我是麦考伊家的
My name is McCoy.
你父亲不会欢迎任何一个麦考伊家的人
Your father would hardly welcome one of us.
不管你听到了什么关于恶魔昂斯・哈特菲尔德
You put everything you heard about devil anse Hatfield
都不要相信
out of your pretty head.
他不是那样的人
He ain't nothing like that.
我就吩咐你们这么一件事
One thing I said to do without fail
务必把你们妹妹带回来!
was bring your sister home!
我们以为她搭马车回家了
We figured she got a ride home.
我们怎么知道?
How was we to know?
我们找过了! 大喊她名字!
We tried! We called out!
她没有回答!
She didn't answer!
我说过务必!
I said without fail!
出去找她
Go find her.
找不到就别回来了
And don't come back till you do.
只有蠢货
Only a goddamn idiot
才会把兰德尔・麦考伊的女儿带回来
would bring randall McCoy's daughter back here,
还是大半夜的
and after midnight.
黑漆漆的晚上 她一个人
Well, she couldn't very well walk back home
要怎么走回家
in the dark by herself.
你不想她待在这 没关系 但...
You don't want her here, that's fine, but...
别再过分责备我
Don't strike me as overgenerous.
该死 我会骑马把她送回家的
Shit, I'll hitch a wagon, ride her back home.
她哪儿也不去
You ain't ridin' her nowheres.
如果被兰德尔・麦考伊看到
The way you make this predicament worse
大晚上的你和他的女儿单独在一起
is for randall McCoy to see you
只会让事情更糟
with his daughter afore sunrise.
他会打爆你的头 而我只会觉得是你活该
He'll shoot your damn head off, and I wouldn't blame him.
那你让我怎么做?
What do you want me to do?
我让你离她远一点
I want you to stay away off o' her, that's what.
莉瓦西 让女孩们为我们的客人
Levicy, have the girls make down a pallet
在地板上铺张草垫
on the floor for our guest.
天一亮 你就把她带到拖轮河谷边界
Come mornin', you take her to the edge of the tug
然后让她自己走
and then leave her off.
遵命
Yes, sir.
还有把你花里胡哨的靴子给我换了
And then get rid of them fancy-nancy boots.
一点男人样都没有
You're supposed to be a workin' man.
漂亮姑娘
Good-lookin' girl.
这可不值得我们去惹麻烦
Yeah, well, it don't make it worth the goddamn trouble.
等麦考伊发现真相的时候 他脸上的表情
The look on McCoy's face when he finds out,
倒是值得一看
that'll be worth seeing.
继续练你的琴吧
You just keep practicin'.
要不换个调
Maybe a different tune.
嘘 继续睡觉
Shh. Go back to sleep.
嗨 嘘
Hi. Shh.
到了我们的蜜月
Oh, and on our honeymoon,
我们就来次真正的火车旅行
we're gonna take a real train ride
走遍大江南北直到我们精疲力尽
all the way across the country till we can't go no more.
我在书上读到俄勒冈州涨潮期的海洋最美最蓝
I read where they got this great blue ocean up in oregon.
这东西大到你无法想象
I mean, this thing's so big and wide,
一望无际
you can't even see the other side.
你哭了?
You cryin'?
为什么?
What on earth for?
我只想知道为何选择我作为你漫长旅途的伴侣
Just wonderin' where I fit in on this long list of conquests.
我美丽 甜蜜的宝贝
My beautiful, sweet darlin'.
你觉得我是在玩弄你?
You think I'm toyin' with you?
我不知该作何感想
I don't know what to think.
这是我的初夜
This is my first time.
我一直想留给我未来的丈夫
I was savin' myself for a husband,
就像上帝告诉我那样
just like god told me to.
我是认真的 罗斯安娜
I ain't foolin' here, roseanna.
我要娶你为妻
I intend to marry you.
要不是我答应了我爸爸
If I hadn't promised my pa,
我会立马冲过这条河
hell, I'd ride on across that river right now,
对你父亲屈膝乞求他的同意
and on bended knee, i'd ask your daddy myself.
下来
Come here.
为娶你为妻 我不惜与世界为敌
I'd go up against the whole world to make you my wife.
我不能改变我的过去或者我的亲人
And I can't change my past or our kin,
但我告诉你
but I tell you true,
我从未对任何人有过这样的感觉
I ain't never felt like this before
直到你的出现
about nobody else but you.
她在那
There she is.
那个约翰斯・哈特菲尔德正在吻她
That's johnse Hatfield a'kissin' on her.
狗娘养的!
That son of a bitch!
你快回去吧
Now get over there.
你告诉他
You tell him.
好
Okay.
- 再见 - 再见
- Bye. - Bye.
我不敢走那座桥
I don't wanna cross that bridge.
我会在这看着你
I'll be here when you get back.
你跑不掉了 约翰斯!
Y'ain't gettin' away, johnse!
哦 我的天哪! 约翰斯!
Oh, my god! Johnse!
约翰斯 是我的兄弟们
Johnse, it's my brothers!
走! 快走!
Go! Go on!
我爱你 罗斯安娜!
I love you, roseanna!
驾!
Ha!
等等! 等等! 停!
Wait! Wait! Stop!
停下来! 别伤害他!
Stop! Don't hurt him!
他什么都没做!
He didn't do nothing!
巴迪 你快阻止他们!
Buddy, buddy, you gotta stop 'em!
爸爸让我们带你回去
We gotta get you to poppy.
我什么都没做!
I didn't do nothing!
抓住他!
Get him!
你死定了!
You're a dead man!
该死的 托尔伯特!
God damn it, tolbert!
你在火大什么?
What you so hot about, anyway?
是你扔下罗斯安娜一个人回不了家的
You're the one that left roseanna with no way home.
我只是为她提供了庇护所和食物
All I did was give her shelter, feed her dinner,
让她免受伤害!
and keep her safe from harm!
你用你一贯作风调戏她了?
You try to have your way with her?
没有 先生!
No, sir!
她昨晚和我妹妹们一起睡的
She spent the night with my sisters.
你也看见她现在安然无恙了
You saw her-safe and sound.
如果我强迫了她
You think she'd be kissin' on me
她还会吻我吗?
if I had violated her in any way?
我确实听到罗斯安娜说...
I did hear roseanna say...
闭嘴 卡尔文
Shut up, calvin.
我们现在杀了他 然后在被发现之前
Now, I say we kill him now and t geon back across the river
迅速穿过河回家
before anyone knows.
听着 你们妹妹知道
Hell, your sister'll know.
她爱我
She loves me.
谎话连篇 满嘴狗屎!
That's a load of bull manure!
不 不是
No, it ain't.
他妈的我也爱她
And I love her too, god damn it.
看来我得证明给你们看
Since I got to prove it to you.
你的枪伤有多严重 约翰斯?
Well, how bad you shot, johnse?
这...这个...
Ha... Well...
我会活下来的
I'll live.
想想子弹都射穿了我的身体
Think the bullet tore straight through me.
托尔伯特 我们走
Tolbert, let's go.
走吧
Come on.
告诉你们爸爸
You tell your pa
我要娶罗斯安娜为妻!
I want to ask roseanna's hand in marriage!
嘿 爸爸! 我们找到她了!
Hey, pa! We found her!
我们找到她了!
We found her!
找到罗斯安娜了!
I got roseanna!
你在哈特菲尔德屋檐下过了一晚?
You spent the night under a Hatfield roof?
和约翰斯的妹妹们在一起
With johnse's sisters, sir.
哈特菲尔德先生好心收留我
Mr. Hatfield kindly gave permission.
约翰斯 他...他想娶我
Johnse, he, uh- He wants to marry me.
你说什么?
Beg your damn pardon?
他爱我 爸爸
He loves me, poppy.
他想取得你的同意
He wants to ask you proper, you know.
他想让一切都名正言顺
He wants to make sure it's right.
他碰了你 罗斯安娜?
He touch you, roseanna?
没有
No.
随便你
You go on.
你想做什么我都不管
Do whatever you want.
这么喜欢哈特菲尔德家的人
You like the Hatfields so much,
你干嘛不永远跟他们待在一起?
why don't you go stay with them forever?
从此以后我们断绝父女关系
You're not my daughter anymore.
你得让拉瑟福德来看看
You'll have to have rutherford take a look at this.
不用 没关系
No, it's fine.
噢!
Ow!
你手拿开
Keep your hand out of the way.
他跟你做的没什么两样
He's gonna do the same thing you're doing.
爸爸 她父亲没有反对
Daddy, her father don't object.
看起来是谁打伤了你
Well, looks like somebody did.
是啊 她愚蠢的兄弟们 噢!
Yeah, her boneheaded brothers-ow!
别动行吗?
Would you hold still?
我没听错吧
I want to hear again that randall McCoy
兰德尔・麦考伊同意把女儿嫁给你
agreed to you marrying his daughter.
不 不完全正确
No, not exactly.
他说他不在乎
He said he don't care.
他不在乎
He don't care.
"不在乎"可算不上是同意
"Don't care" ain't permission.
他在众人面前说的
Well, he said it in front of witnesses.
在你受枪伤之前还是之后 嗯?
Well, was that before or after you got shot, hmm?
事关他的女儿 我可不想激怒麦考伊或任何人
I will not defy McCoy or any man when it comes to his daughter.
爸爸 拜托了 如果你...
Daddy, please, if you...
如果你能同意
If you give permission,
他也会慢慢接受的
he'll surely come around.
去他妈的 孩子! 他们想杀了你!
God damn it, boy! They tried to kill you!
现在你还想娶个那样的?
Now you want to marry into that?
不是这样的
You know what? This ain't right.
我和她想结为夫妻...
Me and her want to be man and wife...
我们都到结婚的年龄了
Now, we're both of age.
别傻了 你才遇到她不久
Don't be a fool. You only just met her.
妈妈...
Mama...
罗斯安娜已经被赶出家门了
Roseanna's been throwed out.
她无处可去
She got no place to go.
你这是在自找罪受 孩子
You're afflicted, son.
好吧
All right.
她可以留在这等她家族来找她
She can stay here until her family comes for her
或者你俩恢复理智了
or you two come to your senses.
谢谢
Thank you.
谢谢你 妈妈
Thank you, mama.
但她要保留自己的姓
But she will keep her own name.
快来
Come on.
噢 小心那条蛇
Oh, watch out for that snake.
我开玩笑的
I'm just kiddin' ya.
我从没见过这般美景
I never knew this existed.
欢迎进入我的生活
Been comin' here my whole life.
这地方是如此美丽
It's so beautiful out here.
是的
Yup.
你在干什么?
What are you doin'?
我的天 约翰斯 你疯了
Oh, my-you are crazy, Johnse.
来和我一起戏水吧
Come get in the water with me.
在这里?
Out here?
在上帝的眼皮底下?
In the eyes of god?
反对我们的又不是上帝
God didn't forbid our union.
是我们的父亲
Our fathers did.
上帝知道在我们心中 彼此早已成婚
God knows we're married in our hearts.
来吧
Come on.
待会见 好吗?
See you later, all right?
什么事?
What's the matter?
哈特菲尔德亲戚
Hatfield kin.
普莱恩错了
Plain ain't right.
一年多了 罗斯安娜还住在哈特菲尔德家里
Over a year now Roseanna's livin' under the Hatfield roof,
脱掉裙子 然后摇身变成
droppin' her skirt and turnin' out to be
任宰任割的鱼肉
just a steady piece of cake.
这一定让哈特菲尔德那老头
Must make old man Hatfield
快活得像只鸡舍里的公鸡
happier'n a banty rooster in a henhouse,
那让我们家族蒙羞
having our family so disgraced.
是的
Yup.
有何贵干?
Help ya?
我是弗兰克・菲利普斯
Frank Phillips.
在肯塔基州路易斯维尔镇平克顿办公室做事
Work outta the Pinkerton office, Pouisville, Kentucky.
我在找鲍勃・莱温格
Lookin' for Bob Levinger.
轮班时没看见鲍勃
Ain't seen Bob in a spell.
要是对一个平克顿的
A fella could get himself into a lot of trouble
持有美国副检察官证的人撒谎
lyin' to a Pinkerton man
那人会惹上一身腥的
with a US Deputy prosecutor warrant.
这足以构成犯罪了
It makes it a federal offense.
我们可以谈谈监狱和罚金
So we're talkin' prison, a big fine.
有人会失去他的小酒馆
A feller could lose his saloon,
以及所有打拼来的东西
everything he's slaved for.
等出狱时 他就是个穷光蛋
Time he's outta jail, he's dead broke.
老婆和某个花心的投机家跑了
His wife's run off with some dandy carpetbagger.
我见过这种事
I seen it happen.
那个玩纸牌的光头
Playin' cards, bald one.
鲍勃・莱温格
Bob levinger.
你没有房屋居住证
You got no paper on where you're livin'.
房子违章搭建 也没缴税
Squatter, payin' no taxes.
书信警告过两次 其中一次是联邦官员发出的
You've been warned twice by mail, once by federal officer.
你得跟我走一趟
I'm here to take you in.
这是拘捕令
This here's a warrant.
这不合法
Ain't legal.
那是哈特菲尔德的地盘
That land is Hatfield.
莱温格是哈特菲尔德的表亲
Levingers is cousins to Hatfield.
我敬爱的叔叔恶魔昂斯
My great uncle Devil Anse,
国土办公室有他登记在案的房屋证明
he got papers on file at the land state office.
一派胡言
Bullshit.
那是政府的财产
It's federal property.
你们这些人以为住在这 就拥有了土地
You people think you're on the land, you own it.
我可不赞同你的说法
I'm sayin' that ain't right.
你可以在法庭上慢慢说
You can tell your story in court.
我认为我不用跟你走
I don't feel like goin' nowheres.
我的弟弟埃德就站在你的后面
My little brother Ed's standing behind you,
拿着一支正规的海军手枪
and he got a regular navy pistol.
你觉得我还需要跟你走吗?
You still think i'm goin' somewheres?
找到一颗
Got one.
另一颗找不到
Can't find the other.
再深一点 可能就会要了你的命
Go much deeper, I might kill you.
当然 若你想的话 我可以再试一次
'course, if you want, I'll give it another try.
你准备去找那个警探吗?
You going after that pinker?
必须去 那混蛋杀了我们的人
Got to. Bastard killed our kin.
吉姆叔叔 我不是在和你说话
I ain't talkin' to you, uncle Jim.
你很清楚莱温格家终会遇到这样的事
You know damn well the Levingers likely had it comin'.
埃德和鲍勃总是一副流氓样
Ed and Bob always was jackasses.
是啊 但他们就是我们家的流氓
Yeah, but they're our jackasses.
有些人认为能对我们的族人开枪
Someone thinks they can take a shot at our kin,
很快别人又觉得他们可以设下埋伏
pretty soon someone else thinks they can lay an ambush
枪杀我们的人
and shoot at one of us.
嘿 你记我们还是小孩子时
Hey, do you remember when we was kids,
爸爸叫我去打死那只鸡舍附近到处嗅的狐狸
pa told me to go shoot that fox nosing around the henhouse.
是的
Yeah.
你不想杀死它
You didn't want to kill it.
你还因此嘲笑我
You poked fun at me for it.
却帮我捉住它 然后就能带它过河
Helped me trap it so's we could take it across the river
放它走
and let it go.
它再没来过
Never come around again.
爸爸他不是一个聪明人
And pa, he was none the wiser.
嗯...
Well...
我要说的是
All I'm sayin' is,
你如此聪明
smart as you are,
或许会找到另一个法子
maybe you can figure out another way.
艾利生 我听到了 但你要知道
I hear you, Ellison, but you should know the reason
那狐狸之所以没再来
that fox didn't ever come around again.
因为你回家后 我杀了它
After you went home, I killed it.
安德森是个好人
Anderson is a good man.
我们家族间的恩怨 呃...
This trouble 'tween our families, well...
让我们所有人都很为难
Well, it makes it hard for all of us.
我想告诉你 在我心里
And I got to tell ya, deep down inside,
不看好你和约翰斯在一起
I ain't got no belief in you and Johnse bein' together.
好吧...
Well...
我们可以在上帝见证下结婚
We can have a union in the sight of god.
你知道的 我们不会
You know, and children that weren't born
未婚生子的
on the wrong side of the bed.
不
No.
不行
你得回到真正属于你的地方
You need to go back to your own, where you belong.
嘿
Hey.
其实你心地不坏
I can see you ain't a bad person,
但这整件事完全不合理
and this whole thing, it ain't right.
你在叫我离开?
You askin' me to leave?
而且最好不要回来
And don't you come back.
你爸爸和安德森之间的争吵
This bullheaded feud between your pa and my Anderson,
就像一种慢性毒药
it's a kind of slow poison.
我继承了五百亩地
I inherited 500 acres,
我会传给你
which I would pass along to you
作为你的嫁妆
on the occasion of your marriage.
但我的土地决不能落入哈特菲尔德手中
But my land will never be in Hatfield hands,
我向你保证
I can promise you that.
妈妈 现在你不用担心了
Don't worry yourself now, mama.
约翰斯和我永远都不会结婚的
Johnse and me ain't never gonna get married.
和哈特菲尔德家玷污你的人断绝关系
Renounce your Hatfield defiler,
你爸爸或许就会让你回家
and your poppy might let you come home.
你曾是他最喜欢的女儿
You used to be his favorite.
到时候你会遇见一个合适的男孩
In time, you'll meet a suitable boy.
妈妈...
Mama-
你...你...
And you-you-
太迟了
It's too late.
我已经两个月没来月事了
I ain't had my flow in two months.
我不知道该怎么办
I don't know what to do.
你怀着哈特菲尔德小杂种回的家?
You come home with a Hatfield bastard in your belly?
嘿 妈妈
Hey, mama.
罗斯安娜在哪?
Where's Roseanna?
回她家族那里了
Gone to her family.
她什么时候回来?
Well, when she comin' back?
不知道她会不会
I don't know that she will.
她不回来 或许对每个人都好
Might be best for all concerned if she don't.
我有七百亩的玉米地
Got 700 acres of corn,
有拖轮叉锯木场12%的股份
12% of the tug fork sawmill,
还有价值近一万美元的票据
and nearly 10,000 in financial instruments.
我唯独缺一个帮手
Only I lack a helpmate,
一个我爱的妻子来分享财产
a loving wife to share my good fortune.
我确定会有很多女人
I'm sure that any number of women
会很乐意迎合你的需求
would be happy to entertain your suit.
我不在乎那些女人
Any number I don't care for.
如果你担心肉体关系方面的事
If you're worried about the physical relations,
我可以忘...
I could forego...
佩里 我不能和你结婚
I can't marry you, Perry.
我怀孕了...
I'm having a baby...
是约翰斯・哈特菲尔德的孩子
Johnse Hatfield's child.
真是不幸
That's unfortunate.
不过我们快点结婚的话
But if we're to marry quickly,
没人会注意孩子不是我的这一悲催事实
no one would catch on to the sad truth the child ain't mine.
否则 你会变成人们的闲话
Otherwise, your condition will be all the gossip, you know,
哈特菲尔德家族的人会取笑这事
the Hatfields laughin' about it.
我爱上了约翰斯・哈特菲尔德
I'm in love with Johnse Hatfield.
贝蒂阿姨?
Aunt Betty?
噢!
Oh!
老天啊 你吓着我了
Sakes alive, you scared me.
甜心 你来这里干什么呢?
What are you doin' here, sugar?
妈妈说你会收留我
Mama said you'd take me in.
没有人想要我了
Ain't nobody else want me.
我们在找一个叫弗兰克・菲利普斯的男人
Lookin' for a gentleman, name of Frank Phillips.
你找他什么事?
What's your business with him?
那肯定是瘸腿恶人弗兰克・菲利普斯
That there must be bad Frank Phillips with that limp.
我姓菲利普斯 但我不叫瘸腿恶人
I go by the name of Phillips, not the other part.
如果我是你 就会管住自己的嘴
So if I was you, i'd mind my tongue.
好吧 你是因为腿瘸了而脾气暴躁?
Well, ain't you ornery for a cripple?
我得好好教你什么是礼貌
I'd give you a lesson in manners,
但在我上楼见珍妮璐之前
but the house required I check my sidearms
赌场要求我检查一下随身武器
'fore I went upstairs with Jenny Lou.
嗯 这挺糟糕的
Well, that's too bad.
鉴于你的态度 我或许乐意看看
Given your attitude, I might like seeing
你用起它们来能有多灵活
how good you could use 'em.
老头 去问问
Well, ask your dead
你家背后开枪的死人亲戚吧
back-shootin' relatives, old man.
菲利普斯先生 我是来和你谈判的
Mr. Phillips, I come here to talk to you,
不是来这该死的妓院和你开枪战的
not have a shootout in a damn whorehouse.
要是我杀了你 我还得向我的妻子解释
After I killed you, I'd have to explain it to my wife,
我并不是很期待那样做 所以...
and I wouldn't much look forward to havin' to do that, so...
相反的 我会请你喝酒
So I'll buy you a drink instead.
哈特菲尔德先生 你就请我喝杯波本威士忌吧
You buy me a bourbon whiskey straight, Mr. Hatfield.
不过最好让你的走狗留在外面
But you have to leave your dog outside.
他可以留下
He can stay.
什么风把你吹来和我谈判?
So why did you make the special trip to parley with me?
我付你一百美金 只要...
I come here to give you $100 on condition-
只要你赶紧离开这里
On condition you move on out of these parts.
我杀了你的族人 为什么还付我钱?
I killed your kin. Why the payoff?
呃 这不是我的初衷
Well, it wasn't my first idea, I promise you.
你在这里待得越久 那些人...
Longer you stay around here, people-
那些人就越期待我对你下手
People expect me to do something about you.
我明白你是在尽你的职责
Now, I understand you were doin' your job,
莱温格家的人 总是最愚蠢的家伙
and Levingers was always damn fool idiots at best,
但不...不要让我成为你的敌人
but don't-don't make me raise my hand against you,
菲利普斯先生
Mr. Phillips.
我会杀了你的
I would kill you.
所以拿着我的钱离开吧
So take my money and ride on out.
我会拿走你的钱  但不要觉得我这是逃跑
I'll take your money. Just don't think I'm runnin'.
你杀了莱温格家的人
You took down the levingers.
别指望能溜走
Didn't expect you to lizard out.
这些个破烂事弄得我全身上下都不给劲
This whole damn thing sticks in my craw,
尤其是受伤的右腿
especially with my bad leg.
在你的地盘 你的亲戚害我丢了工作
It was your land claim and your kin cost me my job.
臭老九
A skunk's profession.
拜托你睁眼看看自己有几斤几两
Get yourself into something useful.
你不能去那儿 约翰斯
You can't go there, johnse.
你喝醉了只会做蠢事
You're all drunk and crazy.
我要跟老麦考伊面对面
I'm gonna stare old man McCoy in the eye.
说清楚
I'm gonna tell him
直截了当告诉他
I'm gonna tell him straight out.
你这是去送死
You're gonna get yourself killed.
别拉着我
Let go of my arm.
他要去肯塔基州跟老兰德尔・麦考伊见面
He wants to ride into kentucky and see old randall McCoy.
我叫南茜・麦考伊 是罗斯安娜的堂姐
Well, I'm nancy McCoy, roseanna's cousin.
我得走了
And I-I gotta go.
听着 你非要去的话
Look, if you go there,
他们会以为你要伤害他们
they're gonna think you mean 'em harm.
那我就大喊 "我不会伤害任何人!
Well, I'll shout out, "i don't mean you no harm!
我就想讲出心声"
I just-I just wanna talk things out."
好吧 如果你和我一起去 你就没事
Well, if you go with me, you'll be safe.
我的马...
Well, my horse...
我们回来的时候再把马牵走
We'll come on back and get it.
你是罗斯安娜的堂姐南茜
You are-you're roseanna's cousin nancy.
赶紧的 我刚刚说过
Go on. That's what I said.
噢!
Oh!
我知道你是谁 你长得有点像她
I know who you are, 'cause you look like her, kind of.
驾!
Yah!
罗斯安娜的堂姐南茜
Roseanna's cousin nancy.
和晚上相比 现在你看起来
You-you kind of look like roseanna in the daylight too.
要更像罗斯安娜一些
More at night, though.
我昨天拜访了我姑妈贝蒂・布兰肯希普一家
I went and visited my aunt betty blankenship's yesterday.
我猜你知道你的未婚妻待在那里
I suppose you know your once-intended is stayin' there.
我不知道
No.
估计老家伙还在为她和我
Guess the old man's still riled
使家族蒙羞而暴跳如雷
at how me and her shamed his family.
对啊 尤其是罗斯安娜还怀孕了
Well, especially now that roseanna's with child and all.
什么?
What?
我要做爸爸了?
I'm gonna be a daddy?
就因为她怀孕了
Because she carries his child,
罗斯安娜觉得自己爱上了约翰斯・哈特菲尔德
roseanna believes herself in love with johnse Hatfield.
爸爸知道这事了吗?
Does our pap know about this?
就他现在的身体状况
Strong as he is,
我担心这事会要了你老头的命
I fear it may break your father's heart.
在他发现之前
Shame we can't remedy the situation
我们一点补救措施都没有 真特么丧气
before he finds out.
如果没有约翰斯
If it weren't for johnse,
罗斯安娜也许能保持理智
roseanna might come to her senses
接受订好的婚约
and accept an offer of honorable marriage.
- 咱们走 - 赶紧的
- Let's go. - Come on.
嗨...
Hey...
你们要干嘛?
What are you doing?
孩子们
Boys.
孩子们!
Boys!
你们这是要去哪儿啊?
Where are you going?
很好...
Well...
我正想找你们
Just the boys I wanna see.
咱们可以一起去你们姑妈贝蒂家
You can ride with me to your aunt betty's house.
我要去那儿解救我的新娘
I'm going there to rescue my bride,
给她一个名分
make an honest woman of her.
闭上你的狗嘴!
Just you shut the hell up!
少来你这套骗人的把戏
You ain't lyin' your way out of it this time.
我没骗人
I ain't lying.
我才得知罗斯安娜怀了我的孩子
Just found out roseanna's carrying my baby.
所以我立马赶去找她
So I'm going to get her,
咱老爸看到肯定会气得冒烟
seeing as how our daddies are being such horses' asses.
你死定了 哈特菲尔德 你别想活着离开!
You're dead, Hatfield. You're gonna be dead!
别碰我 托尔伯特!
Get off of me, tolbert!
你为啥要跟你未来的妹夫过不去?
Why you want to hurt your future brother-in-law?
我要杀了你 你毁了我妹妹的清白!
I'm gonna kill you, 'cause you soiled my sister's honor!
我都说了 我要和她结婚!
I told you, i'm gonna marry her!
卡尔文?
Calvin?
兰德尔?
Randall?
你在干嘛?
What's-what are you doing?
爱丽菲尔 让孩子们回房间
Alifair, get the kids back.
快 快啊!
Git. Git!
你这是干嘛?
What are you doin'?
你喝醉了?
Are you drunk?
你打算瞒着我 对吧?
You weren't gonna tell me, were ya?
我听佩里・克莱因说了
I had to hear it from Perry Cline.
停下 那是罗斯安娜的嫁妆箱
Well, stop. That's roseanna's hope chest.
停下来!
Stop!
我知道是里面装的是什么!
I know what it is!
估计你在奇怪我为什么没直接要你小命
Suppose you's wonderin' why I don't kill you straight away.
因为你知道这样做不对
'Cause you know it ain't right.
放狗屁!
Horseshit!
就像在部队里一样
I'm gonna blow your brains out exactly at sunrise,
天一亮 我就一枪崩了你
like they do in the army.
我就是要你眼睁睁的等死
See, I want you to know it's comin'.
我要你一直被恐惧折磨
And I want you to think about it for all those hours!
让你也尝尝
Feel the kind of torment
你和哈特菲尔德家族的人给我们带来的痛苦
you and all the Hatfields have brought down on us.
我是尊重你妹妹的 托尔伯特
I respect your sister, tolbert.
你知道的
You know that.
更何况她现在怀有我的骨肉
Especially now that she's carrying my baby.
让我去找个牧师来主持我和她的婚礼
Let me go find a preacher and make it legal.
现在说这些太晚了!
Well, it's too late for that!
黎明时分 就是你的死期
I'm gonna shoot you dead come dawn,
我会整点报时
and I'm gonna tell you what time it is
让你知道你离死神越来越近!
every hour we get closer!
我死前能提最后一个请求吗?
Instead of a last meal, can I-can I get a last request?
去你妈的 不行!
Hell, no!
你想要什么?
What do you want?
我想见罗斯安娜最后一面
I want to see roseanna one last time.
我想郑重跟她说一声再见
I want to say good-bye to her in a proper way.
我向天发誓
And then I will stand up tall when you shoot me.
之后我会站直让你枪杀我
I swear to god I will.
等我去了天堂
And when I get to heaven,
我不会诅咒你的灵魂
I won't damn your souls
我会向上帝请求不要
and ask god to send you fryin' to hell
把你送去地狱受惩罚
for what you done to me.
你才是要下地狱的人
You're the one going to hell,
你没有资格在上帝面前提要求
and you ain't gonna be askin' god for squat.
罗斯安娜是爱他的
Roseanna does love him.
我们要是不这么做 她会恨我们一辈子的
She'll hate us forever if we don't allow it.
不行 我说过了!
No, I said!
除了一碗汤
He gets a bowl of stew.
其他的都别想要
Nothing else.
我不喜欢喝汤
That stew didn't set right with me.
你们介意我回家吗?
Do y'all mind if I go home?
当然 兄弟
No, sure, bud.
来吧
Come on.
我们开杀戒的时候 你最好不在场
You shouldn't be here when we do the killin' anyways.
对 你太小了
Yeah, you're too young.
我不小了
I ain't too young.
我就是觉得不舒服 好吗?
I just don't feel so good, all right?
拜了 兄弟
Bye, bud.
该死的 我在阴间等你
Hell, I'll see you on the other side.
我要跟我妹讲话
I got to talk to my sister.
噢 天啊 兄弟
Oh, my god, bud.
你这是干什么去了?
What are you doing out in this?
哈特菲尔德先生!
Mr. Hatfield!
我的兄弟们抓住了约翰斯!
My brothers have got johnse!
他们准备天亮时分杀了他!
They're plannin' on killin' him at dawn!
他在哪儿?
Where is he?
如果我告诉你 你发誓
If I tell you, you got to swear
不要伤害我的兄弟们!
you ain't gonna hurt my brothers!
只要我儿子无恙 你的兄弟们肯定没事
If my son is safe, no harm will come to your brothers.
说 他在哪儿?
Now, where is he?
他们在我叔叔哈蒙家的老房子
They got him at my uncle harmon's old place.
走 走 走 快走
Go, go, go, go, go.
哈特菲尔德先生 拜托你 要快!
Please, Mr. Hatfield, hurry!
赶快 我去给你拿靴子
Go on. I'll get your boots.
拜托!
Please!
约翰斯 我们暂时不会了结你小命
Now, johnse, we wouldn't normally kill you,
直到有一位绅士光明正大的迎娶我妹妹
'cept there's an honorable man willing to marry our sister
那时才是你的死期
soon as you're dead.
是谁?
Who's that?
佩里・克莱因律师答应迎娶罗斯安娜
Lawyer Perry Cline has agreed to make roseanna his wife.
杀夫夺子 还要霸占别人的妻子
Having a man killed to marry their woman and take their baby,
这可不是光明正大行为
that ain't honorable.
还剩一小时 哈特菲尔德
One hour to go, Hatfield.